santhosh.ml@gmail.com

310-666-7446

https://www.linkedin.com/in/santhosh-maila

Founder | Tech Evangelist | Ex-Google

#### <u>Summary</u>

Over the past 20 years I have continuously challenged myself with new languages, frameworks and methodologies. A full stack web developer and have recently been working more with **Angular React/react-native Al/ML** Android Blockchain/Hyperledger Fabric and Composer. An expert in front-end client side technologies, backend server-side technologies and the database technologies.

# Technical Skills:

Angular, TypeScript, Python(Numpy, scikit-learn, keras, PyTorch, Pandas, TensorFlow) RxJS, React/React-Native, Redux/Flux, Hyperledger Fabric / Composer Blockchain, Node.js, JavaScript, IOT, Java, Android, AWS, GCP, Application Architecture, CSS3, REST, SQL,NOSQL(MongoDB, CouchDB)

### Professional Experience

Oportun, San Carlos

09/2021 - Present

Software Developer (IC)

Built client facing loan origination platform (https://apply.oportun.com/home)

Liste Software, San Francisco

03/2020 - 11/2021

Founder

Google, Mountain View

03/2018 - 03/2020

SW Engineer

Conceptual Captions (MLJam ) Designed and Build the Conceptual Captions frontend using Angular6 (http://ai.google.com/research/ConceptualCaptions)

Built FE for Google Crowdsourcing platform (https://crowdsource.google.com/)

Western Digital, Milpitas

07/2016 - 03/2018

Principle Engineer - building your own private cloud

Built the cloud web platform using ReactJS/Redux / React-forms (www.mycloud.com)

Built the IOS/Android application using React Native

(https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.wdc.mycloud&hl=en,

https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/my-cloud-home/id1237361683?mt=8)

Bookbild, San Francisco

03/2016 - 07/2018

Co-Founder, Lead Developer - Blockchain for Middle Market finspace

Used Hyperledger Fabric / Composer to build a blockchain platform for their business needs

Used Angular4 as a Front end for Blockchain UI (http://bookbild.com)

Walmart-labs, Sunnyvale

12/2015 - 07/2016

UI developer/Lead - rebuilding Samsclub.com!

Worked on migrating samsclub.com from the legacy tech stack (Java, JSP, ...) using ReactJS, redux, NodeJS

Hewlett Packard, Palo Alto

04/2014 - 12/2015

SME, Architecture/Engineering Lead - IOT (Wearables) - Movado / Titan / Issac Mizrahi Smart watch Android apps Developed complete app for the smart watches with a 3 member team from the scratch (in 4 months)

Development Lead - IAM Front-End

## Proteus Digital Health, Redwood City

01/2013 - 04/2014

Principal Software Engineer

Architected and implemented an FDA approved Android app which can interact with Bluetooth enabled Medical Patch and Cloud to exchange data.

#### **Education/Technical Certifications**

Master of Science in Computer Science, Diploma in Business Negotionations

Sun Certified Java Programmer, Sun Certified Enterprise Architect, Sun Certified Developer for Java Web Services